{
    "id": "6b8c4d69a164482fac2fffd9cd387eda",
    "title": "Ing Form Or To Infinitive",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The thought ………………………… never entered his head.",
            "description": "The noun thought is followed by of + ing form. The infinitive is not possible in this case.",
            "answers": [
                "to fail",
                "of failing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d5f251959bea4f4499d938094904b1aa"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is quite good ………………………. puzzles.",
            "description": "The adjective good is followed by at + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to solve",
                "at solving",
                "in solving"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f45a69dc52ea4833bc6efa4d14feb91e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am tired ………………………. to your advice.",
            "description": "The adjective tired is followed by of + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to listen",
                "of listening",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "50b4f08a56234d7d90d69ea172bebdc6"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can’t talk without ………………………. your mouth.",
            "description": "When we put a verb after a preposition, it is usually in the ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "opening",
                "to open",
                "open"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "649663b3f8eb49da9cdceeb9f798ce8d"
        },
        {
            "question": "We managed to finish the job by ……………………….. over time.",
            "description": "When we put a verb after a preposition, it is usually in the ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "working",
                "to work"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f928e278ce8549c083ca149e90785988"
        },
        {
            "question": "We repaired the roof instead of …………………………. on vacation.",
            "description": "When we put a verb after a preposition, it is usually in the ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "to go",
                "going"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "bc204565e1234b0f8b3f4421019bba6f"
        },
        {
            "question": "I look forward to ……………………….. a grandmother.",
            "description": "The ‘to’ in the expression ‘look forward to’ is a preposition. We use an ing form after a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "become",
                "becoming",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a06247c8b4f34ee2b1268decac928dc8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not used to ………………………… in big cities.",
            "description": "The ‘to’ in the expression ‘be used to’ is a preposition. We use an ing form after a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "living",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e176b11f10144c2284f2e94fb9853584"
        },
        {
            "question": "He objects to ……………………… on weekends.",
            "description": "The ‘to’ in the expression ‘object to’ is a preposition. We use an ing form after a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "working",
                "work"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3614ef2d4199438fafce0a2327d9f36d"
        },
        {
            "question": "They don’t permit ………………………… in the conference hall.",
            "description": "When there is no object, we use an ing form after permit.",
            "answers": [
                "to smoke",
                "smoking",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "674cb85cdb2b4bb1befb08017ea52c39"
        },
        {
            "question": "We regret ………………………. you that the flight has been cancelled.",
            "description": "Regret is followed by an infinitive in announcements of bad news.",
            "answers": [
                "informing",
                "to inform",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "10d92b29a7d34ec693f7b4d106449469"
        },
        {
            "question": "The principal has forbidden students ……………………….. in the corridors.",
            "description": "When there is an object, we use an infinitive after forbid.",
            "answers": [
                "sing",
                "to sing",
                "singing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "86dee182c9bc4a3798b5ecfa5f4abd06"
        }
    ]
}